Mohamed Hosni Selmi

J (+216) 27 507 236

<u>mohamedhosni.selmi@ensi-uma.tn</u>
<u>m Selmi Hosni</u>

<u>HosniSelmi</u>

https://my-portfolioo-hdzo.onrender.com

Summary

As a professional in the field of Computer Science Engineering with a specialization in Software engineering, I am keen to apply my theoretical and technical knowledge to contribute to the development of innovative technologies in a professional environment.

Education

National School of Computer Science (ENSI)

2021 - 2024

National Engineering Degree in Computer Science, specialty Software Engineering

University of Mannouba

Preparatory Institute for Engineering Studies of Tunis(IPEIT)

2019 - 2021

Preparatory Cycle University Degree in Mathematics and Physics

Tunis

Kairouan Pilot High School (LPK)

2015 - 2019

Bachelor's Degree in Mathematics

Kairouan

Experience

Web Development Internship

Jan 2024 — June 2024

 $Talan_Tunisie$

Charquia 1, Tunis, Tunisia

- Platform Design: Worked in a Scrum Agile team consisting of a Scrum Master, a Product Owner, and 3 developers.
- Back-End Development: Use Symfony to implement the logic for managing online stores, including product and order management.
- Front-End Development: Create an intuitive user interface using Vite React, allowing users to customize their e-commerce site in real-time with a live preview of the changes.
- Payment and Delivery System: Integrate secure online payment systems and delivery options, taking into account security and privacy standards resulting in a 30% increase in successful transactions.
- Technologies: symfony, vite React, Mysql, Git, Jenkins, Docker.

Internship in DevOps

June 2023 — Aug 2023

ADERFIA INC

Kairouan, Tunisia

- Working in Teams: Collaborated with a team of 7 members, including 3 backend developers, 2 frontend developers, and 2 DevOps engineers, to develop and deploy microservices architecture
- Database Management: Enhanced data management efficiency by 20% through the implementation of MongoDB as the database for data storage, designing data schemas, and managing data access.
- Containerization with Docker and Build Automation with Jenkins: Created Docker containers for the microservices and their dependencies, ensuring easier and reproducible production deployment. Set up Jenkins to automate the source code build processes upon each change, including unit and integration testing.
- Technologies: symfony, Doctrine, MongodB, Git, Jenkins, Docker. kubernetes, Cloud

Web Development Internship

June 2022 — Aug 2022

Market 360 Degrees

- Work on Specification Development and Project Planning.
- Designing and Developing Business Logic, Database Management, APIs, and Application Processing Workflows.
- Creating User Interface, Web Pages, Application Forms, and Features for Recruiters.
- Implementing Security Measures to Protect Sensitive Candidate Data.
- Technologies: ReactJS, NodeJS, ExpressJS, Elasticsearch.

Technical Skills

Programing Languages: Python, C/C++, Java, JavaScript, TypeScript, SQL.

Markup Languages: HTML, CSS.

Frameworks/Libraries: ExpressJS, NestJS, ReactJS, React Native, Flask, Spring Boot, Angular, Django, Sumfony, Bootstarp.

Developer Tools: VS Code, Eclipse IDE, Android Studio.

DBMS: Oracle Database, Mysql, Mongodb, Elasticsearch.

Data Visualization Libraries: Matplotlib, Seaborn, Scikit-learn, Tensorflow.

Machine Learning Technologies: Machine Learning, Deep Learning, Data Mining. Mathematics Knowledge: Statistics, Probability, Linear Algebra, Graph Theory.

Communication: English (Fluent speaker), French (Fluent speaker), Arabic (Native), Spanish (Beginner-level)

Tunis, Tunisia